Neugass, Fritz; Papers ger007
M.E. Grenander Department of Special Collections & Archives
- Museums & Private Collections, 1950s-1979; 2; 148 file folders
  - Barnes, Albert C. Foundation, Merion, PA, Opening for the Public, 1961 (Box 8 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 38)
    Also auction in Philadelphia 1967 of the collection Nelle Mullen, Secretary of Barnes. Typescripts (5), photographs (3), publicity, clippings.
  - Basel, Kunstmuseum, Undated (Box 8 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 39)
    Typescript, correspondence.
  - Bass, John. Florida Museum, Undated (Box 8 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 40)
    Typescripts (4) including clippings, photographs (2), clippings.
  - Bauhaus. Book review of Bauhaus 1919-1928, edited by Bayer and Gropius, 1952 (Box 9 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 1)
  - Berkeley, University Museum. Some notes, no text, Undated (Box 9 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 2)
    Photographs (4), publicity.
  - Boston Museum of Fine Arts. 100th year centenary exhibit "Art Treasures for Tomorrow", 1970 (Box 9 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 3)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (38), publicity, clippings.
  - Carnegie Institute, Pittsburgh. Exhibits, 1952; 1955 (Box 9 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 4)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (15), publicity, catalogs, clippings.
  - Carnegie Institute, Pittsburgh. Exhibit, 1958-1959 (Box 9 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 5)
    Typescript, photographs (24), publicity, catalog, clippings.
  - Carnegie Institute, Pittsburgh. Exhibit, 1961 (Box 9 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 6)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (29), publicity, catalog, clippings.
  - Carnegie Institute, Pittsburgh, 1964-1965 (Box 9 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 7)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (16), publicity, catalog, clippings.
  - Carnegie Institute, Pittsburgh, 1967-1968 (Box 9 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 8)
    Typescript, photographs (13), publicity, catalog, clippings.
  - Carnegie Institute, Pittsburgh, 1970-1971 (Box 9 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 9)
    Manuscript, notes, photograph, publicity, catalog, clippings.
  - Carnegie Institute, Pittsburgh, Undated (Box 9 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 10)
    Exhibition catalogs (2).
  - Carnegie Institute, Sarah Scaife Gallery, Undated (Box 9 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 11)
    Photographs (7), publicity, clippings.
  - Christina of Sweden. Exhibit of her collections in Stockholm, 1966 (Box 9 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 12)
  - Chrysler Collection at Norfolk Museum (Walter P. Chrysler Jr.), forgery scandal, Undated (Box 9 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 13)
    Typescripts (4), photographs (3), publicity, clippings.
  - Clark, Robert Sterling, Undated (Box 9 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 14)
    Typescript, notes, photographs (13), publicity, clippings.
  - Clark, Stephen C., Undated (Box 9 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 15)
    Photographs of paintings by old and modern masters, given by Clark to Metropolitan Museum and to Yale University. No text by Fritz Neugass. Photographs (15).
  - Cleveland Museum of Art, Undated (Box 9 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 16)
    Short text, exhibition catalogues, photographs (52).
  - Cleveland Museum of Art, Undated (Box 9 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 17)
    Publicity, clippings.
  - Colin and Spingold Collections. Exhibited in New York, 1960 (Box 9 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 18)
    Typescript, photographs (21), publicity, clippings.
  - Contini-Bonacossi, Count Alessandro, Collection in Florence, Undated (Box 9 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 19)
    Typescripts (2), photograph, publicity, clippings.
  - Cooper-Hewitt Museum. Opening in 1976, no article by Fritz Neugass, Undated (Box 9 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 20)
    Photographs (9), publicity, clippings.
  - Corcoran Gallery Bienniale, Washington D.C., 1965 (Box 9 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 21)
  - Dale, Chester. Collection in Washington, Undated (Box 9 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 22)
    Typescripts (2), notes, photographs (24), publicity, clippings.
  - Denver Art Museum. Opening of the new museum building, 1971 (Box 9 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 23)
    No text by Fritz Neugass. Photographs (4), publicity.
  - d'Harnoncourt, René. "A Tribute", Memorial by the Museum of Modern Art, 1968 (Box 9 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 24)
  - Dresden Museum. Also exhibit in Zurich, 1971 (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 1)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (15), correspondence, publicity, clippings.
  - Dresden exhibit in U.S. "The Splendor of Dresden", 1978 (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 2)
    Typescript, photographs (16), publicity, clippings.
  - Florence: Die Uffizien, Undated (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 3)
    Typescript, photographs (6), correspondence, clippings.
  - Freer Gallery, Washington. 50th Anniversary, 1973 (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 4)
    Typescript, photographs (4), correspondence, publicity.
  - Frick Collection, New York. 50th Anniversary, Undated (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 5)
    Typescript, notes, clippings.
  - Getty, J. Paul. Museum in Malibu, California, Undated (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 6)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (4), correspondence, publicity, clippings.
  - Glazier, William S. Collection of illuminated manuscripts, donated to the Morgan Library, 1968 (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 7)
    Typescripts (2), publicity, clippings.
  - Guggenheim, Peggy. Collection, Undated (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 8)
    Typescripts (3), photographs (22), clippings.
  - Guggenheim, Solomon R. Foundation, Undated (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 9)
    Museum, photographs from various exhibits and from art works of the museum's collections, no article by Fritz Neugass.
    See also under Architecture. Photographs (70).
  - Gulbenkian, Carlouste Sarkis. Collection exhibited in Washington, Undated; typescript (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 10)
  - Gutenberg, Johannes. Exhibit on occasion of 500-year-jubilee at Grolier Club, NY, 1966 (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 11)
    1968, also book review of Lehmann-Haupt, "Gutenberg and the Masters of the Playing Cards".
    Typescripts (3), photographs (4), publicity, clippings.
  - Hammer, Armand. Hermitage State Museum, Leningrad; Hammer Galleries, New York, Undated (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 12)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (10).
  - Hanley, T. Edward. Exhibit of collection in New York, 1967 (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 13)
    Typescript, photographs (3), publicity, clippings.
  - Harriman, Honorable W. Averell, Undated (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 14)
    Photos (7) of works from the Ecole de Paris from the Harriman Collection, exhibited in the National Gallery in Washington, 1961, no text.
  - Hartford, Huntington. Collection and museum in New York, Undated (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 15)
    Typescripts (4), photographs (4), publicity, clippings.
  - Hearst, William Randolph. Hearst mansion, San Simeon, Undated (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 16)
    Typescripts (2), notes, photographs (20), publicity, clippings.
  - Hirshhorn, Joseph H. Sculpture collection in Guggenheim Museum, 1962 (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 17)
    Hirshhorn Museum, Washington, 1974, also exhibit of Émigré Artists, 1976. Typescripts (6), photographs (19), publicity, clippings.
  - Hitler and Goering. Art works plundered in the Third Reich, Undated (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 18)
    Typescripts (2), photograph, correspondence, clippings.
  - Houghton Library, Harvard University. Book review of the publication on occasion of its 25th Anniversary, Undated; typescript, clippings (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 19)
  - Iowa, University of. Museum of Art opening 1969, with illustrated catalogs, Undated (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 20)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (11), publicity, clippings.
  - Janis, Sidney and Harriet. Collection given to Museum of Modern Art, Undated (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 21)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (27), publicity, clippings.
  - Jarves, James Jackson. Collection of old masters at Yale University, including illustrated catalog, Undated (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 22)
    Typescripts (3), photographs (2), clippings.
  - Jerusalem Museum, Undated (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 23)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (21), publicity, clippings.
  - Karolik, Maxim. Collection and donation of American art, with proof of the catalogue, texts in German and English, Undated (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 24)
  - Kimbell Art Museum, Fort Worth, TX, Undated; typescript, clippings (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 25)
  - Kress, Samuel H. Disposal of art collection, Undated (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 26)
    Typescripts (6), photographs (65), publicity, clippings.
  - Leningrad, Hermitage, 1957 (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 27)
    Printed article by Fritz Neugass and inscriptions on photos, 1975, on occasion of the traveling exhibit in the USA. Typescript, photographs (3), publicity, clippings.
  - Lewisohn, Samuel A. Impressionist collection exhibited at Metropolitan Museum, 1951 (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 28)
  - Loewenich, Karl. Old masters from his collection, Undated (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 29)
    Typescripts (3), clippings.
  - London National Gallery, Undated (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 30)
    Typescript, notes, photographs (7), clippings.
  - Los Angeles County Museum. Opening, 1965 (Box 10 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 31)
    Typescript, photographs (8), publicity.
  - Los Angeles art galleries. Catalogs, etc., no notes or text by Fritz Neugass, Undated (Box 11 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 1)
  - Louvre, Paris, Undated (Box 11 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 2)
    Typescript, notes, photographs (12), clippings.
  - Lytton Center of the Visual Arts, Los Angeles. Catalogs, publicity, clippings, no text by Fritz Neugass, Undated (Box 11 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 3)
    Photographs (36).
  - May, Morton D. Collection of modern German Art, Undated (Box 11 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 4)
    Also correspondence with the collector. Typescript, photographs (13), publicity, clippings.
  - Mellon, Paul and Alisa. Collection of English Art at Yale University, Undated (Box 11 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 5)
    Typescript, notes, photographs (2), publicity, clippings.
  - Metropolitan Museum, New York. Articles and materials on the history and exhibits of the Museum, Undated (Box 11 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 6)
    Typescripts (9), photographs (28), publicity, clippings.
  - Metropolitan Museum. New acquisitions, Undated (Box 11 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 7)
    Typescripts (5), photographs (19), publicity, clippings.
  - Metropolitan Museum. Greek vases, including Calyx Krater, Undated (Box 11 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 8)
    Typescripts (5), notes, photographs (24), publicity.
  - Metropolitan Museum. Greek vases, Undated; clippings (Box 11 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 9)
  - Metropolitan Museum. Controversial sale of art works from the museum's collection under Thomas Hoving, Undated (Box 11 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 10)
    Typescripts (8), notes, clippings.
  - Metropolitan Museum. Thomas Hoving, Director of the Museum, 1966-1976 (Box 11 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 11)
    No texts by Fritz Neugass. Publicity, clippings.
  - Metropolitan Museum. New attributions of art works, Undated (Box 11 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 12)
  - Metropolitan Museum. 100th Anniversary 1970, "Masterpieces of Fifty Centuries" exhibit, Undated (Box 11 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 13)
  - Metropolitan Museum. 100th Anniversary exhibit "The Year 1200", Undated (Box 11 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 14)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (28), clippings.
  - Metropolitan Museum. The Robert Lehman Collection and the new Lehman Wing, 1975 (Box 11 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 15)
    Typescripts (6), photographs (26), publicity, clippings, incl. 4 by Neugass.
  - Metropolitan Museum, Exhibit "In the Presence of Kings", 1966 (Box 11 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 16)
  - Metropolitan Museum. Summer Loan exhibits from private collections, Undated (Box 11 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 17)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (27), publicity, catalogs.
  - Metropolitan Museum. The Cloisters, Exhibit of medieval art from private collections, Undated (Box 11 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 18)
    Typescripts (3), photographs (48), publicity, clippings.
  - Metropolitan Museum. The Cloisters. Calendar and photographs (4) of an illuminated manuscript, Undated (Box 11 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 19)
  - Metropolitan Museum. The Junior Museum, Undated (Box 11 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 20)
  - Metropolitan Museum. The Wrightsman Galleries, Undated (Box 11 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 21)
  - Metropolitan Museum. Bundles of photos of various bequests and exhibits, no articles by Fritz Neugass, Undated (Box 11 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 22)
    Photographs (88), publicity, clippings.
  - Metropolitan Museum. CINOA (International Confederation of Dealers in Works of Art) exhibition, 1975 (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 1)
  - Metropolitan Museum. Musical instrument collections of André Mertens Galleries and Crosby Brown Collection. No notes or text by Fritz Neugass, Undated (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 2)
    Photographs (2), publicity.
  - Metropolitan Museum. Art of the Near East, Turkey. No notes or text by Fritz Neugass, Undated (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 3)
    Photographs (30), publicity.
  - Metropolitan Museum. Art of the Far East. Some notes, no finished text, Undated (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 4)
  - Metropolitan Museum. Annenberg bequest offer, 1976 (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 5)
    No notes or text by Fritz Neugass, publicity, clippings.
  - Milwaukee Art Institute. No notes or text by Fritz Neugass, Undated (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 6)
    Photographs (6), catalogs, publicity, clippings.
  - Munich museums, Undated (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 7)
    Publicity, photographs (6).
  - Museums in the United States. Articles on the development and politics of American museums and their purchases, Undated (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 8)
    Typescripts (13), photographs (11), publicity, clippings.
  - Museum of Modern Art, New York, Undated (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 9)
    Includes 1959 design exhibit "Toward a new Museum of Modern Art", no text by Fritz Neugass. Photographs (20), publicity, clippings.
  - Museum of Modern Art. 25th anniversary, 1954 (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 10)
  - Museum of Modern Art. Reopening, 1964 (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 11)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (30), publicity, clippings.
  - Museum of Modern Art. Protests against the Museum, 1940; 1960 (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 12)
    Original photos by Neugass. Typescript, photographs (5), publicity, clippings.
  - Museum of Modern Art. Exhibit "Modern Masters: Manet to Matisse", 1975 (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 13)
  - National Gallery, Washington, Undated (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 14)
    Typescript, captions for photographs, publicity.
  - National Gallery, Undated (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 15)
    Photographs (69), publicity.
  - National Gallery. 10th and 15th anniversaries, 1951; 1956 (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 16)
    Typescripts (2), publicity.
  - National Gallery. 25th anniversary, also the Museum and its donors, 1966 (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 17)
    Typescripts (5), notes, photographs (8), publicity, clippings.
  - National Gallery. The Mellons as donors: Andrew, Mr. and Mrs. Paul, Alisa Mellon Bruce, 1966 (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 18)
    Typescript, photographs (49), clippings.
  - National Gallery. The new East Wing, 1978 (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 19)
  - Neuberger, Roy R. Collection of 20th century American art, Neuberger Museum, Purchase, NY, including Knoedler catalog and lists, no article by Fritz Neugass, Undated (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 20)
    Photographs (6), publicity, clippings.
  - Niarchos, Stavros, Undated (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 21)
    Typescript, photographs (23), clippings.
  - Pearlman, Henry, Undated (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 22)
  - Philadelphia Museum, Undated (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 23)
    Including the Louis E. Stern Collection, also Tyson and Arensberg Collections.
    Typescripts (3), photographs (22), publicity, clippings.
  - Pierpont Morgan Library, New York, Undated (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 24)
    Typescripts (8), notes, photographs (127).
  - Pierpont Morgan Library, Undated (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 25)
  - Prado Museum, Madrid. 150th Anniversary, 1969 (Box 12 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 26)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (16), clippings.
  - Quinn, John, Undated (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 1)
    Typescript, notes, photographs (10), publicity, clippings.
  - Das Rijksmuseum, Amsterdam, Undated (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 2)
  - Robinson, Edward G. Collection, Undated (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 3)
    Including catalogues of the collection from Museum of Modern Art.
  - Rockefellers. The Rockefeller family as collectors and patrons of art, Undated (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 4)
    Including list and catalog of the exhibit "A Family Collects" at Knoedler.
    Typescripts (2), photographs (27).
  - Rockefellers. Portraits of the Rockefellers and photos from the opening of the exhibit "A Family Collects", Undated (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 5)
    Includes original photos by Fritz Neugass. Photographs (31), publicity, clippings.
  - Rockefeller, Nelson. His Collections, Undated (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 6)
    Also controversies regarding his reproductions of art.
  - Rockefeller, Nelson. Museum of Primitive Art, Rockefeller private museum, West 54th Street, material for several exhibits, no text by Fritz Neugass, Undated (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 7)
    Photographs (73), publicity, clippings.
  - Rosenwald, Lessing J. Collector of graphic arts and donor, Undated (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 8)
    Typescripts (2), notes, clippings.
  - Sachs, Paul J. Exhibit of his collection in Fogg Art Museum, 1965 (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 9)
  - Sao Paulo, Brazil. Various biennales, also exhibit of the Sao Paulo Museum in the Metropolitan Museum, 1957 (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 10)
    Typescripts (5), photographs (18), publicity, clippings.
  - Schimmel, Norbert. Collection of works of antiquity, exhibited in the Metropolitan Museum, 1975 (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 11)
  - Scholz, Janos. Collection of Italian Drawings, numerous handwritten notes by Fritz Neugass, but no finished article, Undated (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 12)
    Photographs (12), publicity, catalogs, clippings.
  - Seligman, Germain. Obituaries, book review of "Merchants of Art", Undated (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 13)
    Typescripts (3), notes, photographs (3), clippings.
  - Simon, Norton, Undated (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 14)
    Typescripts (7), photographs (16), publicity.
  - Smithsonian Institution. Traveling exhibitions, history of the museum, Undated (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 15)
    Typescript, photograph, correspondence, publicity, clippings.
  - Soby, James Thrall. Collection of Modern Art, exhibit at Knoedler, 1961 (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 16)
  - Stein, Gertrude and family. Exhibit "Four Americans in Paris", in Museum of Modern Art, with printed text by Fritz Neugass, Undated (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 17)
    Photographs (9), catalog, publicity, clippings.
  - Texas Collectors. Exhibit at Marlborough-Gerson with catalogue, 1964 (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 18)
    Typescript, photographs (5), clipping.
  - Thannhauser, Justin K. Collection given to Guggenheim Museum, Undated (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 19)
    Including 3 typed pages of resume, with handwritten notes by Thannhauser.
    Typescripts (3), photographs (18), publicity, clippings.
  - Thompson, G. David. Collection of modern art, Undated (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 20)
    Including report on the auction of 1966.
    Typescripts (4), drafts, photograph, publicity, clippings.
  - Valentiner, Wilhelm Reinhard, Director, North Carolina Museum. Memorial exhibition, with special memorial issue of the museum bulletin, Undated; typescript, clippings (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 21)
  - Venedig: Venice. Biennale, 1966; 1968 (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 22)
    Typescripts (2), photographs (24), clippings.
  - Vienna, Kunsthistorisches Museum, Undated (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 23)
    Photographs (11) for the Fritz Neugass series of great museums for the "Elegante Welt", no Fritz Neugass text preserved.
  - Vollard, Ambroise. Exhibit at the Museum of Modern Art, 1977 (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 24)
    Typescripts (2), notes, photographs (4), publicity, clippings.
  - Wadsworth Athenaeum, Hartford, CT, Undated (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 25)
  - Washington, National Collection of Fine Arts, Undated (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 26)
    Photographs (21), publicity, no text by Fritz Neugass.
  - Wildenstein Gallery, Felix Wildenstein, Undated (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 27)
    Several articles, including 75th jubilee of the firm.
    Typescripts (5), photographs (41).
  - Collectors and Collections, Undated (Box 13 (2-Museums & Private Collecti), Folder 28)
    Typescripts (2), clippings, printed materials.
- Art market, art auctions, 1950-1979; 3; 217 folders
  This series contains typescripts by Neugass, photographs and clippings on various art auctions and reviews of art seasons from 1950-1979. The bulk of this series (148 file folders) consists of articles on (Sotheby) Parke-Bernet auctions. The articles have been arranged chronologically by date and Sale Number, which correspond to the Sotheby Parke-Bernet auction catalogs in Series 16 (Boxes 62-75).
  Please see Series 16 for the full auction catalogs in which the articles from Series 3 appear.
  Arranged chronologically.
  - Art Market, international and American. Fundamental and summary articles by Neugass, Undated (Box 14 (3-Art market, art auctions), Folder 1)
    20 in German, 3 in English.
  - Art Prices of individual works, Undated (Box 14 (3-Art market, art auctions), Folder 2)